<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects | JIN IGARASHI</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/project/</link><atom:link href="https://jin-igarashi.me/en/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Projects</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©Jin IGARASHI 2023</copyright><image><url>https://jin-igarashi.me/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>Projects</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/project/</link></image><item><title>Japanese Translation for Input mobile app</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/project/202101-input/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/project/202101-input/</guid><description>&lt;p>I started to translate iOS and Android mobile mapping application - &lt;a href="https://inputapp.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Input&lt;/a> from English to Japanese since January 2021.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In Japan, there are a lot of users who are using iPhone and iPad, however there is no longer available for mobile solution of QGIS in Japan. I finally translated Input app to Japanese language for QGIS community in Japan. Now Japanese users have multipul choices either QField or Input for mobile.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Open Source Project for Water Vector Tile app</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/project/202002-narok-vectortile-project/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/project/202002-narok-vectortile-project/</guid><description>&lt;p>I developed a simple &lt;a href="https://github.com/watergis/awesome-vector-tiles" target="_blank" rel="noopener">open source tools&lt;/a> to create and deploy vectortiles easily.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Currently, the following water services providers are using my tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://narok.water-gis.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Water Supply Map for Narok Water, KENYA&lt;/a>: since June 2020.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://rural.water-gis.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Water Supply Map for WASAC RWSS, RWANDA&lt;/a>: since July 2020.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://nakuru.water-gis.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Water Supply Map for Nakuru Water, KENYA&lt;/a>: since August 2020.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>This tool is using direct SQL to create vectortiles from your PostGIS database. So, my tool can adopt any PostGIS database easily. If there is already PostGIS in your organizaiton, it is so fast to be able to host your vectorties. But please also contact me if you do not have PostGIS database yet. I will support your organization to develop PostGIS database and adopt it for vectortiles.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Japanese Translation for QField mobile app</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/project/201909-qfield/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/project/201909-qfield/</guid><description>&lt;p>I started to translate Android mobile mapping application - &lt;a href="https://qfield.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">QField&lt;/a> from English to Japanese since September 2019.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I met Mr. Matthias (OpenGIS.ch) at code sprint of FOSS4G 2019 Bucharest, then I got involved QField project. QField is great tool and very much compatible with QGIS. I wish I can constribute to Japan&amp;rsquo;s QGIS community to use it more and more in field.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can see some of my translation from &lt;a href="https://qfield.org/docs/ja/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Survey for the Establishment of the Experimental Field for the GNSS System Development in the Kingdom of Thailand</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/project/201811-thai_cors/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 22:11:16 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/project/201811-thai_cors/</guid><description>&lt;p>Period: November 2018 to November 2019&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Client: The Gevernment of Thailand&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Project for Strengthening Operation and Maintenance of Rural Water Supply Systems in Rwanda (RWASOM project)</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/project/201806-rwasom/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 22:09:24 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/project/201806-rwasom/</guid><description>&lt;p>Period: June 2018 to December 2019&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Client: Water and Sanitation Corporation Ltd, Rwanda&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Conducted training workshops for data collection and sharing with FOSS4G applications, then designed &amp;amp; created GIS database and data sharing platform for rural water supply management in RWASOM project. Collaborated with Rwandan colleagues to complete mapping all of water supply systems in the country. The system in Rwanda uses PostGIS, Lizmap/QGIS Server, QGIS Desktop, QField and Garmin GPS.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Preparatory Survey for the Project for Strengthening Nzove-Ntora Principal Water Transmission Pipeline in Kigali City, Rwanda</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/project/201710-nzove-ntora/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 22:05:50 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/project/201710-nzove-ntora/</guid><description>&lt;p>Period: October 2017 to November 2018&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Client: Water and Sanitation Corporation Ltd, Rwanda&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The GIS project in Narok Water, Kenya</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/project/201404narok-water/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 08:45:17 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/project/201404narok-water/</guid><description>&lt;p>Period: April 2014 to September 2016&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Client: NAROK WATER AND SEWERAGE SERVICES CO., LTD., KENYA&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Worked as a GIS specialist funded by JICA and conducted the following activities.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Mapped the entire water distribution network (approximately 300km length of pipeline in Total) in Narok and Ololulung’a town (Trimble GPS, ArcPAD, QGIS).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Designed and developed GIS database &amp;amp; WebGIS (PostGIS, Mapserver, Leafletjs). The system links to billing system, it helps improve their revenue collections.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Created the DMAs (District Metered Areas) for analyzing and improving Non-Revenue water management.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Conducted training to transfer technical knowledge to Kenyan colleagues, then GIS system is continuously being used up to now since it has been developed.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Consulted GIS work for 7 water services providers (Nyeri water, Kabarnet water, Kapsabet water, Nakuru water, Nakuru rural water, Naivasha water and Mavoko water) in Kenya.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Software developments in Fujitsu</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/project/200904-fujitsu_ssl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 22:15:19 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/project/200904-fujitsu_ssl/</guid><description>&lt;p>Period: April 2009 to March 2017&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Designed and developed following GIS applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the development of HD map for autonomous vehicle (ArcGIS Server, Python, Django REST framework).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>the system of mapping and simulating location of ships’ movement in Singapore (Leafletjs).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Web-GIS system for the Real Property Registration system in Ministry of Justice of Japan (Mapserver, OpenLayers, Oracle).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>An Android application for health care management (Java).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>An area marketing system by using MapInfo.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Logistics and distribution management system with Dijkstra routing algorism (VB.NET, SQL Server, MS Access).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>