<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks | JIN IGARASHI</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/</link><atom:link href="https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©Jin IGARASHI 2024</copyright><image><url>https://jin-igarashi.me/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/</link></image><item><title>[FOSS4G2023] UNDP's one stop shop for cloud based geospatial data visualisation and analytical tool</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20230629_foss4g2023_undpgeohub/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20230629_foss4g2023_undpgeohub/</guid><description>&lt;p>United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) is a United Nations agency tasked with helping countries eliminate poverty and achieve sustainable economic growth and human development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recent advances in technology and information management have resulted in large quantities of data being available to support improved data driven decision making across the organization. In this context, UNDP has developed a corporate data strategy to accelerate its transformation into a data-driven organisation. Geo-spatial data is included in this strategy and plays an important role in the organization. However, the large scale adoption and integration of geo-spatial data was obstructed in the past by issues related to data accessibility (silos located in various country offices), interoperability as well as sub-optimal hard and soft infrastructure or know-how.
All this issues have been addressed recently, when UNDP SGD integration started developing a geospatial hub - GeoHub - to provide geospatial data visualisation and analytical tools to UNDP staff and policymakers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>UNDP GeoHub is a repository of a wide array of data sets of the most recent time span available at your fingertips! It is a centralized ecosystem of geospatial data and services to support development policymakers. It allows users to search and visualise datasets, compute dynamic statistics and download the data. In addition, GeoHub provides a feature to share their maps with the community easily. With our repository, you can also upload to share your valuable data to share with the community! It connects geospatial knowledge and know-how across the organization to enhance evidence-based decision-making with relevant data-led insights.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Geohub ecosystem consists of sveltekit &amp;amp; maplibre based frontend web applications and various FOSS4G software in the backend side. PostgreSQL/PostGIS, titiler, pg_tileserv and martin are deployed in Azure Kubernetes (AKS) to provide advanced visualisation and analysis for users. All source code is published in Github with an open-source license.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>[abstract] (&lt;a href="https://talks.osgeo.org/foss4g-2023/talk/8TFHPG/">https://talks.osgeo.org/foss4g-2023/talk/8TFHPG/&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JCgNnMAtCI4?si=382QBrFSW12EFZ6s" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe></description></item><item><title>[FOSS4G2023] Development of maplibre applications in sveltekit</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20230628_foss4g2023_svelte/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20230628_foss4g2023_svelte/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, sveltekit is becoming a more popular framework for developing web application. It has been released as v1.0.0 last December. However, there are still not many use cases of developing maplibre applications in sveltekit compared to other frameworks like react. The author is involved in developing maplibre application with sveltekit in United Nations Development Programme (geohub), and also developing sveltekit based Web-GIS applications for water asset management at Eastern African countries (watergis). Hence, several useful maplibre boilerplate and components were developed in sveltekit during those projects' work. watergis/sveltekit-maplibre-boilerplate is a template which can start developing maplibre application in sveltekit with minimuum source code. Furthermore, watergis/svelte-maplibre-components consists of various useful maplibre components to add more functionality easily to your web application (all components are documented here). For instance, this component library provides you features of exporting maps, adding legends, styling maps, sharing maps, measuring distance and integrating with Valhalla api, etc. In this talk, these maplibre boilerplate and components will be briefly introduced.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>[abstract] (&lt;a href="https://talks.osgeo.org/foss4g-2023/talk/CL9XDK/">https://talks.osgeo.org/foss4g-2023/talk/CL9XDK/&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gWyA0I3SipA?si=kjB8ZjiBd4c76dtp" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe></description></item><item><title>[FOSS4G2022] Rural water supply mapping by using FOSS4G application in Rwanda</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20211001_foss4g2021_watergis-copy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 09:30:00 -1000</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20211001_foss4g2021_watergis-copy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Water and Sanitation Corporation (WASAC) started mapping rural water supply system in Rwanda since 2018. WASAC conducted the data collection by using QGIS, QField and PostGIS all over the country of Rwanda, and now all GIS data is available as open data and visualized in this website by using Mapbox Vector Tiles. WASAC is trying to achieve universal access to water in SDGs Goal 6 by keeping updating and utilizing GIS data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are developing GIS system as open source, and all of source code was developed in Github through WASAC organization repositories here under the collaboration with The United Nations Vector Tile Toolkit team. Our approach uses quite low-cost technologies which are more sustainable in low and middle-income countries. All our data is also available in OpenAFRICA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our achievements of the project were presented in previous global conference of FOSS4G 2019 Bucharest and FOSS4G 2021 Buenos Aires. In FOSS4G 2022, we would like to update our current situation of the GIS system to the community.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>[abstract] (&lt;a href="https://talks.osgeo.org/foss4g-2022/talk/WGLMQ8/">https://talks.osgeo.org/foss4g-2022/talk/WGLMQ8/&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>[FOSS4G2022]Rural water supply mapping by using FOSS4G application in Rwanda</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20220826_foss4g2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 09:30:00 -1000</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20220826_foss4g2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>Water and Sanitation Corporation (WASAC) started mapping rural water supply system in Rwanda since 2018. WASAC conducted the data collection by using QGIS, QField and PostGIS all over the country of Rwanda, and now all GIS data is available as open data and visualized in this website by using Mapbox Vector Tiles. WASAC is trying to achieve universal access to water in SDGs Goal 6 by keeping updating and utilizing GIS data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are developing GIS system as open source, and all of source code was developed in Github through WASAC organization repositories here under the collaboration with The United Nations Vector Tile Toolkit team. Our approach uses quite low-cost technologies which are more sustainable in low and middle-income countries. All our data is also available in OpenAFRICA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our achievements of the project were presented in previous global conference of FOSS4G 2019 Bucharest and FOSS4G 2021 Buenos Aires. In FOSS4G 2022, we would like to update our current situation of the GIS system to the community.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>[abstract] (&lt;a href="https://talks.osgeo.org/foss4g-2022/talk/WGLMQ8/">https://talks.osgeo.org/foss4g-2022/talk/WGLMQ8/&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>[FOSS4G2021]An implementation of FOSS4G - QGIS, QField and Vector Tiles for rural water supply management in Rwanda</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20211001_foss4g2021_wasac/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 10:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20211001_foss4g2021_wasac/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>[abstract] (&lt;a href="https://callforpapers.2021.foss4g.org/foss4g2021/talk/3HWXNF/">https://callforpapers.2021.foss4g.org/foss4g2021/talk/3HWXNF/&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This talk was presented by my colleague - Mr. Moise Irankunda from WASAC, Rwanda.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe src="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vTA3eInyJchu18QOd30Llpon2YpmU10D5PJ9NrL9wUzXAarxd7Z1D_OsLmLTVJ-Yw/embed?start=false&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=3000" frameborder="0" width="960" height="569" allowfullscreen="true" mozallowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true">&lt;/iframe></description></item><item><title>[FOSS4G2021]The impact of application of FOSS4G on Non Revenue Water</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20211001_foss4g2021_nanyuki/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 09:30:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20211001_foss4g2021_nanyuki/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>[abstract] (&lt;a href="https://callforpapers.2021.foss4g.org/foss4g2021/talk/39FPCS/">https://callforpapers.2021.foss4g.org/foss4g2021/talk/39FPCS/&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This talk was presented by my colleague - Mr. James Njenga from Nanyuki water, Kenya.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>[QGIS Open Day] Open Education for QGIS</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20210226_qgis_open_day/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20210226_qgis_open_day/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I joined Mr. Hans&amp;rsquo;s session on QGIS Open Day, its title was &lt;a href="https://github.com/qgis/QGIS/wiki/QHF-February-2021#open-education-for-qgis" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Open Education for QGIS&lt;/a>. Last year, I translated some training materials of &lt;a href="https://courses.gisopencourseware.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GIS OpenCourseWare&lt;/a> which Mr. Hans launched for open education. I am also translater for both &lt;a href="https://qfield.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener">QField&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://inputapp.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Input&lt;/a> mobile applicaiton. I told my motivation for traslating QGIS related documents and softwares.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="video">Video&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The below is youtube video for the session.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fxf7ydKigeY" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe></description></item><item><title>[JICA Webinar] A case study of Open Source GIS in rural water management in Rwanda</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20210118_jica_webinar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 18:00:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20210118_jica_webinar/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="summary">Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I presented &amp;ldquo;A case study of Open Source GIS in rural water management in Rwanda&amp;rdquo; in JICA webinar. I introduced what we developed in Rwanda and what we are doing for rural water management by using open source GIS now. Also we focused our future planning of development for next phase GIS system in WASAC, Rwanda. In webinar, we presented in Japanese language together with French interpreter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The title in French was &amp;ldquo;Etude de cas sur l’exploitation du WebSIG pour l’approvisionnement en eau en milieu rural par l’intégration du logiciel à code source ouverte au Rwanda&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In presentation day, there were two Rwandan colleagues from WASAC joined as observor, it was really successful.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="slide">Slide&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The below is my slide for this presentation in French.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe src="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vQdZh8ZQL97islw051zlOLOsnbeZBnDNUKpJjp17KqCWQXJYPer-ZLS5y-A2jXS3w/embed?start=false&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=3000" frameborder="0" width="960" height="569" allowfullscreen="true" mozallowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true">&lt;/iframe></description></item><item><title>[FOSS4G Korea 2020] Use cases of Vector Tiles implementation for water utilities in Eastern Africa</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20201113_foss4g_korea_2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 12:40:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20201113_foss4g_korea_2020/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In Eastern Africa, most of water utilities already have some GIS data. However, they often have some challenges to utilize and share the data within the entire organization. I was involved the projects in Kenya and Rwanda since 2014. Recently, I found a sustainable way to share GIS data through vector tiles as open data. I would like to introduce these open source tools which I developed for them.
The following website is a documentation for my open source softwares.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://docs.water-gis.com">https://docs.water-gis.com&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="slide">Slide&lt;/h2>
&lt;iframe src="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vTLVaKKtopofh_tITh_PUSh_tKlYKdjy7RmmJg1O_dSlvG7cKO4FyYJIa9vOPyKfp46PreA1n3LkP-E/embed?start=false&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=3000" frameborder="0" width="960" height="569" allowfullscreen="true" mozallowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true">&lt;/iframe></description></item><item><title>[WaQuAc-Net Webinar] A cheap and easy way to utilize GIS for effective management of water utility</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20201028_waquacnet_gis_webinar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 17:30:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20201028_waquacnet_gis_webinar/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>GIS systems are widely used in the water supply field in the world. However, most of GIS systems have high license fees and training costs for development, maintenance, and operation, and there are not many examples of effective use in the water supply utilities in general. Mr. Igarashi , lecturer will introduce a low-cost, easy-to-build GIS system that uses open source technology called Vector Tiles. He built it in Kenya and Rwanda as a GIS system that can be accessed by all staff of water utilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="slide">Slide&lt;/h2>
&lt;iframe src="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vRnbniVVm1_Epili5j4fc5wYQZa3VeAUsncvLlCq3-aG-2xBf6sFDPz6X71XgVMYVcw9bpZAcKhm9aV/embed?start=false&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=3000" frameborder="0" width="960" height="569" allowfullscreen="true" mozallowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true">&lt;/iframe></description></item><item><title>[FOSS4G Hokkaido 2020] Vector Tiles implementation for water services providers in Eastern Africa</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20200926_foss4g2020_hokkaido/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 11:55:00 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20200926_foss4g2020_hokkaido/</guid><description>&lt;p>Although it is presentation in Japanese language&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe src="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vQRyhbW_jbsu7B0Xuta61O5jWLUAbMqbiakdIFflXJlFFkUSxnelSaMixwTW2SADlrcS2k6hrYQdW8G/embed?start=false&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=3000" frameborder="0" width="960" height="569" allowfullscreen="true" mozallowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true">&lt;/iframe></description></item><item><title>[FOSS4G2019]Case Study of Data Collection &amp; Data Sharing for Rural Water Supply Management in Rwanda</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20190830_foss4g2019_rwanda/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 22:27:27 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20190830_foss4g2019_rwanda/</guid><description>&lt;p>Water and Sanitation Corporation (hereinafter, called WASAC) and Japan International Cooperation Agency (hereinafter, called JICA) are coducting the project for strengthening operation and maintenance of Rural Water Supply Systems in Rwanda (hereinafter, called RWASOM) since 2015. RWASOM mainly supports 4 model districts - Rwamagana, Kayonza, Ngoma and Kirehe at the Eastern Province in Rwanda. The project conducts developments of manual and capacity building of WASAC, Districts and Private Operators.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Currently, most of countries focus SDGs to achieve 100% water access by 2030. Because of that, it is very necessary to collect and analyse the GIS inventory data for water supply management, especially planning and improvement of operation and maintenance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now WASAC has started to map all of water facilities data in rural area under support of RWASOM since July 2018. Then, we also started to use collected data by offline since Feb 2019.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We spent the minimum budget to conduct our mapping and data sharing without customizing FOSS4G so much. This our approaches might be very useful for other users in developing countries. So we would like to share our experience and approach of FOSS4G in Rwanda.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="512" height="288" src="https://media.ccc.de/v/bucharest-30-case-study-of-data-collection-data-sharing-for-rural-water-supply-management-in-rwanda/oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>See the video from &lt;a href="https://media.ccc.de/v/bucharest-30-case-study-of-data-collection-data-sharing-for-rural-water-supply-management-in-rwanda" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>[FOSS4G2019]Case Study of Non-Revenue Water Management of Narok water in Kenya</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20190828_foss4g2019_kenya/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 22:24:22 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/talk/20190828_foss4g2019_kenya/</guid><description>&lt;p>Narok Water and Sewerage Services Company (hereinafter, called NARWASSCO) supplies water at Narok town and Ololulung&amp;rsquo;a town in Kenya. As of February 2019,we have 4,689 water connections and 74,314m3 of water consumption in Narok, also have 580 water connections and 5,736m3 of water consumption in Ololulung&amp;rsquo;a. Total length of pipeline is 144.2km in Narok and 71.7km in Ololulung&amp;rsquo;a.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NARWASSCO, currently uses FOSS4G to do data collection and data utilization for water supply services. For example, mapping of all water facilities in the company, and the collected data have been used to improve operations (application of new connection, leakage management, meter reading, customer care, etc.). We can say Narok water is the first water company which started to use FOSS4G in Kenya.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our interesting is how water company use GIS inventory data to reduce Non-Revenue Water (NRW). NRW means physical losses(leakage) and commercial losses(meter reading error, illegal connection, etc.). We think GIS technology can contribute a lot of things for water supply services, so we would like to share our experience and get some idea from participants of FOSS4G conference.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="512" height="288" src="https://media.ccc.de/v/bucharest-135-case-study-of-non-revenue-water-management-of-narok-water-in-kenya/oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>See the video from &lt;a href="https://media.ccc.de/v/bucharest-135-case-study-of-non-revenue-water-management-of-narok-water-in-kenya" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>