<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Larissa Dusabe | JIN IGARASHI</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/ja/authors/larissa-dusabe/</link><atom:link href="https://jin-igarashi.me/ja/authors/larissa-dusabe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Larissa Dusabe</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>ja-JP</language><copyright>©Jin IGARASHI 2024</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 09:30:00 -1000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://jin-igarashi.me/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>Larissa Dusabe</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/ja/authors/larissa-dusabe/</link></image><item><title>[FOSS4G2022]Rural water supply mapping by using FOSS4G application in Rwanda</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/ja/talk/20220826_foss4g2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 09:30:00 -1000</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/ja/talk/20220826_foss4g2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>Water and Sanitation Corporation (WASAC) started mapping rural water supply system in Rwanda since 2018. WASAC conducted the data collection by using QGIS, QField and PostGIS all over the country of Rwanda, and now all GIS data is available as open data and visualized in this website by using Mapbox Vector Tiles. WASAC is trying to achieve universal access to water in SDGs Goal 6 by keeping updating and utilizing GIS data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are developing GIS system as open source, and all of source code was developed in Github through WASAC organization repositories here under the collaboration with The United Nations Vector Tile Toolkit team. Our approach uses quite low-cost technologies which are more sustainable in low and middle-income countries. All our data is also available in OpenAFRICA.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our achievements of the project were presented in previous global conference of FOSS4G 2019 Bucharest and FOSS4G 2021 Buenos Aires. In FOSS4G 2022, we would like to update our current situation of the GIS system to the community.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>[abstract] (&lt;a href="https://talks.osgeo.org/foss4g-2022/talk/WGLMQ8/">https://talks.osgeo.org/foss4g-2022/talk/WGLMQ8/&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>[FOSS4G2019]Case Study of Data Collection &amp; Data Sharing for Rural Water Supply Management in Rwanda</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/ja/talk/20190830_foss4g2019_rwanda/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 22:27:27 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/ja/talk/20190830_foss4g2019_rwanda/</guid><description>&lt;p>以下、アブストラクトです。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Water and Sanitation Corporation (hereinafter, called WASAC) and Japan International Cooperation Agency (hereinafter, called JICA) are coducting the project for strengthening operation and maintenance of Rural Water Supply Systems in Rwanda (hereinafter, called RWASOM) since 2015. RWASOM mainly supports 4 model districts - Rwamagana, Kayonza, Ngoma and Kirehe at the Eastern Province in Rwanda. The project conducts developments of manual and capacity building of WASAC, Districts and Private Operators.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Currently, most of countries focus SDGs to achieve 100% water access by 2030. Because of that, it is very necessary to collect and analyse the GIS inventory data for water supply management, especially planning and improvement of operation and maintenance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now WASAC has started to map all of water facilities data in rural area under support of RWASOM since July 2018. Then, we also started to use collected data by offline since Feb 2019.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We spent the minimum budget to conduct our mapping and data sharing without customizing FOSS4G so much. This our approaches might be very useful for other users in developing countries. So we would like to share our experience and approach of FOSS4G in Rwanda.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="512" height="288" src="https://media.ccc.de/v/bucharest-30-case-study-of-data-collection-data-sharing-for-rural-water-supply-management-in-rwanda/oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://media.ccc.de/v/bucharest-30-case-study-of-data-collection-data-sharing-for-rural-water-supply-management-in-rwanda" target="_blank" rel="noopener">こちら&lt;/a>からビデオをご覧下さい。&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>