<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ronoh Kennedy | JIN IGARASHI</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/ja/authors/ronoh-kennedy/</link><atom:link href="https://jin-igarashi.me/ja/authors/ronoh-kennedy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Ronoh Kennedy</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>ja-JP</language><copyright>©Jin IGARASHI 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://jin-igarashi.me/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>Ronoh Kennedy</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/ja/authors/ronoh-kennedy/</link></image><item><title>Does “Low Cost” Urban Sanitation Exist?</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/ja/publication/narok-cactus-paper/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/ja/publication/narok-cactus-paper/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this paper, we report results from, and demonstrate the value of, a global database for the collection and aggregation of reliable and comparable cost data for urban sanitation systems as they are built and operated on the ground (rather than the “as planned” costs that are often reported). We show that no particular “mode” of urban sanitation (for example “sewered sanitation” or “fecal sludge management”) can be meaningfully described as “low cost” when compared to other modes. We show that economies of scale may operate for systems that transport waste from pits and sealed tanks by road as well as for sewerage. We use a case study example to show the value of being able to compare local costs to global benchmarks and identify that operational considerations such as low connection rates may be more significant in determining overall cost liabilities for urban sanitation than technical considerations such as population density, size, and degree of centralization/decentralization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read the full text at &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.3c05731" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DOI: 10.1021/acs.est.3c05731&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>[FOSS4G2019]Case Study of Non-Revenue Water Management of Narok water in Kenya</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/ja/talk/20190828_foss4g2019_kenya/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 22:24:22 +0900</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/ja/talk/20190828_foss4g2019_kenya/</guid><description>&lt;p>以下、アブストラクトです。&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Narok Water and Sewerage Services Company (hereinafter, called NARWASSCO) supplies water at Narok town and Ololulung&amp;rsquo;a town in Kenya. As of February 2019,we have 4,689 water connections and 74,314m3 of water consumption in Narok, also have 580 water connections and 5,736m3 of water consumption in Ololulung&amp;rsquo;a. Total length of pipeline is 144.2km in Narok and 71.7km in Ololulung&amp;rsquo;a.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>NARWASSCO, currently uses FOSS4G to do data collection and data utilization for water supply services. For example, mapping of all water facilities in the company, and the collected data have been used to improve operations (application of new connection, leakage management, meter reading, customer care, etc.). We can say Narok water is the first water company which started to use FOSS4G in Kenya.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our interesting is how water company use GIS inventory data to reduce Non-Revenue Water (NRW). NRW means physical losses(leakage) and commercial losses(meter reading error, illegal connection, etc.). We think GIS technology can contribute a lot of things for water supply services, so we would like to share our experience and get some idea from participants of FOSS4G conference.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="512" height="288" src="https://media.ccc.de/v/bucharest-135-case-study-of-non-revenue-water-management-of-narok-water-in-kenya/oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://media.ccc.de/v/bucharest-135-case-study-of-non-revenue-water-management-of-narok-water-in-kenya" target="_blank" rel="noopener">こちら&lt;/a>からビデオをご覧下さい。&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>