<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sanitation | JIN IGARASHI</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/categories/sanitation/</link><atom:link href="https://jin-igarashi.me/en/categories/sanitation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Sanitation</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©Jin IGARASHI 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://jin-igarashi.me/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url><title>Sanitation</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/categories/sanitation/</link></image><item><title>Does “Low Cost” Urban Sanitation Exist?</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/publication/narok-cactus-paper/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/publication/narok-cactus-paper/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this paper, we report results from, and demonstrate the value of, a global database for the collection and aggregation of reliable and comparable cost data for urban sanitation systems as they are built and operated on the ground (rather than the “as planned” costs that are often reported). We show that no particular “mode” of urban sanitation (for example “sewered sanitation” or “fecal sludge management”) can be meaningfully described as “low cost” when compared to other modes. We show that economies of scale may operate for systems that transport waste from pits and sealed tanks by road as well as for sewerage. We use a case study example to show the value of being able to compare local costs to global benchmarks and identify that operational considerations such as low connection rates may be more significant in determining overall cost liabilities for urban sanitation than technical considerations such as population density, size, and degree of centralization/decentralization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read the full text at &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.3c05731" target="_blank" rel="noopener">DOI: 10.1021/acs.est.3c05731&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shit-flow diagram (SFD) Lite report in Narok town, Kenya</title><link>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/publication/naroktown-sfd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jin-igarashi.me/en/publication/naroktown-sfd/</guid><description>&lt;p>Narok town is Narok county’s capital city which is the largest city on the way to Maasai Mara National Reserve from Nairobi. It became a municipality in October 2019 due to the rapidly growing population. Figure 2 shows the official municipality boundary and demographical data from the latest census in 2019. The municipality covers the area of Narok Township (Narok Town &amp;amp; Oleleshwa), Nkareta (Nkareta, Naisuya &amp;amp; Olopito) and part of Ololulunga ward (Ereteti &amp;amp; Nkoben) (Narok County, 2021. The population and the number of households are 117,609 and 31,757 respectively.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>60% of excreta generated is safely managed and the rest (40%) is unsafely managed. The safely managed excreta originate from FS contained - not emptied (32%), wastewater delivered to treatment and treated (2%) and FS delivered to treatment and treated (26%). The unsafely managed excreta originate from wastewater delivered to treatment but not treated (1%), wastewater not delivered to treatment (1%), FS delivered to treatment but not treated (1%), FS not delivered to treatment (9%), FS not contained - not emptied (14%) and open defecation (16%).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please see full SFD lite report from &lt;a href="https://sfd.susana.org/about/worldwide-projects/city/304-narok-town" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>